Ryan Skeans

ryanskeans@gmail.com https://github.com/skeanster 951-234-1872 San Diego, CA

Summary

Software engineer with a track record of working well with stakeholders and delivering efficient solutions. Through my work experience, I have developed a strong understanding of how to utilize modern tech stacks to create reusable and extensible UI components that integrate perfectly with efficient API's. I am excited to continue expanding and enhancing my skillset as part of an excellent team.

Experience

Software Engineer

SS&C Advent • San Francisco, CA

04/2023 - Present

- Integrated both REST and GraphQL API's into our application
- Utilized custom CSS properties to create a cohesive and easily adaptable UI
- · Contributed to UI design system by developing generic and extensible web components
- Wrote and tested front end features using the cypress testing framework
- Excelled in an agile environment to meet client needs in an iterative fashion

Associate Software Engineer

SS&C Advent • San Francisco, CA

02/2022 - 04/2023

- Developed front end interfaces for an enterprise focused SAAS product
- Utlized a modern tech stack including Sass, Lit (React-like JS framwork), Typescript, Cypress, Web Components, and Material
- Collaborated with teams of engineers, product managers, and designers to develop pixel perfect solutions based on client feedback
- Created extensible, reusable, and generic web componenets that fit into the companies overall design system
- Leveraged a Javascript data visualiztion framework to create dynamic, data driven SVG charts
- Employed CSS variables to extend a maintainable front end platform

Senior Product Management Associate

Prudential Financial • San Francisco, CA

07/2020 - 02/2022

- · Worked to build and enhance Prudential's retail/direct to consumer products
- Analyzed and provided insights on KPI's using Tableau and Adobe Analytics
- Participated in design sprints aimed at providing the customer with the best experience possible

Education

B.S. Business Administration, Financial Management

California Polytechnic State University - San Luis Obispo • San Luis Obispo, CA

06/2020

Top Skills

React, Web Components, Typescript, JavaScript, Node.js, HTML, SQL, Express.js, Webpack, Sass, Material, CSS, Git, GitHub, Cypress, NPM, Node.js, Python